Register of the Joan Kennedy Taylor papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Joan Kennedy Taylor papers
1955-2004
2007C7
Hoover Institution Archives
27 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes (11.6 linear feet)
Taylor, Joan Kennedy
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2007.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Joan Kennedy Taylor was born in Manhattan on December 21, 1926, to Joseph Deems Taylor and Mary Kennedy. Her father was a well-known composer and radio personality and her mother was an actress and a poet. After her parents divorced, Kennedy Taylor attended a number of schools in various parts of the world. She received her higher education at Barnard College, where she met her husband, Donald Cook, who was a psychology student at neighboring Columbia University. The couple was engaged in 1947 and married a year after. In January of 1950 their only son, Michael Cook, was born. The marriage did not last and in 1953, Cook and Kennedy Taylor were divorced.
Shortly after the marriage ended she started working at Alfred A. Knopf in the publicity department and became involved with the literary world. It was there that Kennedy Taylor was first introduced to Ayn Rand through the advance copy of, Atlas Shrugged. Her fascination with the novel led her to write a fan letter to Rand sparking a life-long friendship.
In 1958 Kennedy Taylor enrolled as one of the first students of the Nathaniel Branden Institute, where she took a course on ‘Basic Principles of Objectivism.’ It is there that her friendship with David Dawson, a writer, turned into a romance. The two married later that year and remained married for over twenty years until Dawson’s death in 1979. By the 1960s Joan Kennedy Taylor became more interested in politics and it was around this time that she helped found the Young Republicans Club in New York and served as the editor of the group’s newsletter. She was also responsible for transforming the newsletter into a libertarian magazine, Persuasion. Additionally, she worked alongside Roy A. Child, Jr., as an associate editor of The Libertarian Review. In the 1980s, Kennedy Taylor continued her writing career as the publication director at the Manhattan Institute where she was responsible for bringing to light the work of Charles Murray, a notable political scientist. While working at the institute she served as an editor of the Freeman magazine.
Kennedy Taylor’s list of accomplishments is extensive, especially when it comes to her involvement in libertarian feminism and writing for notable publications such as: The Wall Street Journal, Washington Times, Reason, Inquiry, Success, American Enterprise, Stanford Law & Policy Review, and the Journal of Information Ethics. She wrote numerous monographs and articles, and was a commentator for a nationally syndicated radio show, Byline. In 1992 Kennedy Taylor wrote her first book entitled, Reclaiming the Mainstream: Individualist Feminism Rediscovered, and followed it with her 1999 publication, What to Do When you Don’t Want to Call the Cops: A Non-Adversarial Approach to Sexual Harassment. Kennedy Taylor died on October 29th, 2005.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection documents the professional career of Joan Kennedy Taylor and includes her writings, and activities within the field of libertarian feminism. The collection contains numerous issues of newsletters, bulletins and magazines. It also includes various articles, monographs, and literary reviews done by Kennedy Taylor as well as the writings of other individuals on topics such as Ayn Rand, libertariansim, objectivism, pornography, and psychology. Additionally housed within the collection are audio tapes, transcripts of radio broadcasts, conference materials, research materials, and materials relating to courses taught by Joan Kennedy Taylor.
Related Collection(s)
Roy A. Childs, Hoover Institution Archives
Feminism--United States.; Journalists.; Libertarianism--United States.; Phonotapes.
- Byline Radio Show file, 1981-1988
  Scope and Contents
  Comprised of promotional materials, transcripts of broadcasts, and a 33 ½ rpm disc of the nationally syndicated radio show, Byline, of which Kennedy Taylor was a regular commentator. Please refer to the Sound Recordings series for tapes and the 33 ½ rpm disc of Byline broadcast recordings.
  - Articles, 1984 (Text : 1: 1)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Text : 1: 2)
  - Promotional Campaign, 1981 (Text : 1: 3)
  - Scripts, 1986-1988 (Text : 1: 4)
- Individual Files, 1967-1997
  The series is composed of files on various individuals with whom Joan Kennedy Taylor had a professional and personal relationship. The files are mainly composed of documents on Martin and Annelise Anderson, Camille Castorina, Roy A. Childs Jr., and Victor Niederhoffer.
  - Anderson, Martin and Annelise, 1967-1993 (Text : 1: 5)
  - Castorina, Camille, 1983-1997 (Text : 1: 6)
  - Childs, Roy A. Jr. (Biographical File), 1969-1992 (Text : 1: 7)
  - Childs, Roy A. Jr., 1993-1995 (Text : 1: 8)
  - Childs, Roy A. Jr. (Estate), 1992-1993 (Text : 2: 1)
  - Niederhoffer, Victor (Junto), 1991-1997 (Text : 2: 2)
- Printed Materials File, 1955-2004
  Composed of copies of newsletters, bulletins, and journals to which Joan Kennedy Taylor had subscribed to, or for which she had written articles and reviews. Some of the newsletters and bulletins in this series include: AAPS, Association of Libertarian Feminists, Berkshire Women’s Libertarian Newsletter, The Freeman, Frontlines, Inquiry, ISIL: Freedom Network News, Law and Liberty, Libertarian Review, Persuasion, Reason, Success, Women’s Choice, and The Women’s Freedom Newsletter.
  - AAPS (Association of American Physicians and Surgeons) News, 1991-1994 (Text : 2: 3)
  - AAPS Pamphlets, 1990-1993 (Text : 2: 4)
  - Association of Libertarian Feminists, 1989-1996 (Text : 2: 5)
  - Association of Libertarian Feminists, 1997-2001 (Text : 2: 6)
  - Berkshire Women's Libertarian Newsletter, 1972-1973 (Text : 2: 7)
  - Foundations of Liberty, circa 1990 (Text : 3: 1)
  - Free Inquiry, 2001-2002 (Text : 3: 2)
  - Free Market, 1983 (Text : 3: 3)
  - Free Press Network, 1984-1990 (Text : 3: 4)
  - Free Texas, 1981 (Text : 3: 5)
  - The Freeman, 1956-1973 (Text : 3: 6)
  - The Freeman, 1978-1985 (Text : 3: 7)
  - Frontlines, 1981-1982 (Text : 3: 8)
  - Ideas on Liberty, 1955 (Text : 3: 9)
  - Inquiry, 1982-1984 (Text : 3: 10)
  - Interdisciplinary Journal - Legal Studies Forum, 1985-1986 (Text : 4: 1)
  - Interdisciplinary Journal - Legal Studies Forum, 1987-1988 (Text : 4: 2)
  - Interdisciplinary Journal - Legal Studies Forum, 1988-1989 (Text : 4: 3)
  - International Society for Individual Liberty - Freedom Network News, 1986, 1987 (Text : 4: 4)
  - International Society for Individual Liberty - Pamphlets, 1988-2000 (Text : 4: 5)
  - Journal of Interdisciplinary Legal Studies - Alsa Forum, 1982 (Text : 4: 6)
  - Journal of Interdisciplinary Legal Studies - Alsa Forum, 1982 (Text : 5: 1)
  - Law and Liberty, 1979-1981 (Text : 5: 2)
  - Libertarian International Chronicle, 1981-1982 (Text : 5: 3)
  - Libertarian International Free World, 1981-1982 (Text : 5: 4)
  - Libertarian International Free World Chronicle, 1982-1984 (Text : 5: 5)
  - Libertarian International Free World Chronicle, 1984-1986 (Text : 5: 6)
  - Libertarian Law Notes, 1978-1980 (Text : 5: 7)
  - Libertarian Review, 1977-1978 (Text : 5: 8-9)
  - Libertarian Review, 1979-1981 (Text : 6: 1-3)
  - Liberty, March - November, 1998 (Text : 6: 4)
  - Liberty, January - June, 1999 (Text : 6: 5)
  - Liberty, July - December, 1999 (Text : 7: 1)
  - Liberty - Massachusetts, 1975-1982 (Text : 7: 2-9)
  - Liberty - Massachusetts, circa 1984 (Text : 7: 10)
  - Manhattan Report, 1983 (Text : 7: 11)
  - The Objectivist Forum, 1980-1981 (Text : 7: 12)
  - Persuasion, 1964 (Text : 7: 13)
  - Persuasion, 1965 (Text : 8: 1)
  - Persuasion, 1966 (Text : 8: 2)
  - Persuasion, January - June, 1967 (Text : 8: 3)
  - Persuasion, July - December, 1967 (Text : 8: 4)
  - Persuasion, January - May, 1968 (Text : 8: 5)
  - Persuasion (Original Printing), 1964 (Text : 29: 1)
  - Persuasion (Original Printing), 1965 (Text : 29: 3)
  - Persuasion (Original Printing), 1966 (Text : 29: 3)
  - Rational Individualist, December, 1968 - December, 1969 (Text : 9: 1)
  - Reason, 1969 (Text : 9: 2)
  - Woman's Choice, 1978-1980 (Text : 9: 3)
  - Woman's Choice - Administrative, 1978-1980 (Text : 9: 4)
  - Women's Freedom Network Newsletter, 1994-1999 (Text : 9: 5)
  - Women's Freedom Network Newsletter, 2000-2004 (Text : 9: 6)
  - §7201 Report, 1983-1985 (Text : 9: 7)
  - Various Libertarian Newsletter, 1970-2000 (Text : 10: 1-2)
- Research Files, 1967-2000
  Comprised of research materials reflecting the interests and professional focus of the creator. Materials in the section pertain to abortion, child welfare, feminism, healthcare, housing, objectivism, pornography, race, workfare, and women’s right issues, domestic and abroad.
  - Abortion, 1990-1993 (Text : 10: 3)
  - Abortion and Sterilization Decisions, circa 1970 (Text : 10: 4)
  - Articles and Reprints, 1977-1982 (Text : 10: 5)
  - Articles and Reprints, 1979-1999 (Text : 10: 6)
  - Classics, 1970-1997 (Text : 10: 7)
  - Classics, 1989-1993 (Text : 11: 1)
  - CommLaw Conspectus Article - Workplace Sexual Harassment, 1996 (Text : 11: 2)
  - Copeland - Medicare, 1991-1998 (Text : 11: 3)
  - Copeland - Medicare (Health Care Fight - Correspondence), 1990-1994 (Text : 11: 4)
  - Feminism, 1991-1997 (Text : 11: 5)
  - Feminism and Women, 1978-1993 (Text : 11: 6)
  - Free Country Project, 1991 (Text : 12: 1-2)
  - Housing, zoning, land-use, horror stories, 1976-1995 (Text : 12: 3)
  - Innovative Inner Cities, 1987-1991 (Text : 12: 4)
  - Leo House, 1998 (Text : 12: 5)
  - Libertarian Organization, 1979-1993 (Text : 12: 6)
  - Libertarian Organization, 1967-1981 (Text : 12: 7)
  - Libertarian Organization, 1967-1981 (Text : 13: 1)
  - Objectivists, 1991-1998 (Text : 13: 2)
  - Papers and Clippings, circa 1987 (Text : 13: 3)
  - Race, 1977-1995 (Text : 13: 4)
  - Schwartz, Gene, 1990-1998 (Text : 13: 5-6)
  - William F. Weld, 1992 (Text : 13: 7)
  - Women Abroad, 1997-1998 (Text : 13: 8)
  - Women and Military, 1981-2000 (Text : 13: 9)
  - Workfare, 1995-1999 (Text : 14: 1)
- Speaking Engagements and Courses File, 1974-2002
  Comprised of conference proceedings and various speaking engagements attended by Joan Kennedy Taylor. Some of the conferences includes: Advancing Liberty Conference, Cato Seminar, Free Inquiry Conference, Hoover Institution Conference on National Service, Libertarian Party Convention, Liberty and the Land Ethics Conference, New Country Conference, New School Panel, Salt Lake City Convention, Symposium of Secularism, WNBA Panel. The series also includes materials from a course taught by Joan Kennedy Taylor at the New School entitled, “Women and the Law.”
  - Annual National Libertarian Party Convention, 6th, July 14-17, 1977 (Text : 14: 2)
  - Association of American Physicians and Surgeons Conference, October 8, 1993 (Text : 14: 3)
  - Cato Institute's Summer Seminars in Political Economy, July 4-11, 1981 (Text : 14: 4)
  - The Eris Society Conference, August 5-9, 1992 (Text : 14: 5)
  - Foundation for Economic Education, Convention, May 3-5, 2002 (Text : 14: 6)
  - Free Inquiry Conference, May 1990 (Text : 14: 7)
  - Free Inquiry on Secularism Symposium, Summer, 1992 (Text : 14: 8)
  - Hoover Institution Conference on National Service, September 8-9, 1989 (Text : 14: 9)
  - The Hoover-Rochester Conference on the All-Volunteer Force, December 13-14, 1979 (Text : 14: 10-11)
  - Independent Women's Forum - Managing the Media, February 22, 1996 (Text : 14: 12)
  - Libertarian International, "20th Anniversary of the Movement,", August 30th, 1989 (Text : 15: 1)
  - Libertarian International World Convention, August 24-29, 1982 (Text : 15: 2)
  - Libertarian International World Convention, 1st, August 14-19, 1983 (Text : 15: 3)
  - Libertarian International World Convention, 2nd, August 13-19, 1984 (Text : 15: 4)
  - Libertarian International World Convention, 3rd, August 21-27, 1986 (Text : 15: 5)
  - Libertarian Lawyers Conference, September 6-7, 1979 (Text : 15: 6)
  - Libertarian National Convention and Political Expo, September 2-5, 1993 (Text : 15: 7)
  - Libertarian Party Convention, 1979 (Text : 15: 8)
  - Libertarian Party Convention, California, August 15-17, 1980 (Text : 15: 9)
  - Libertarian Party Convention, Massachusetts, April 1, 1978 (Text : 15: 10)
  - Libertarian Party Convention, New York, May 29-31, 1981 (Text : 15: 11)
  - Libertarian Party Platform, 1974-1981 (Text : 15: 12)
  - Libertarian Party Platform, 1979-1980 (Text : 15: 13)
  - Libertarian Party Tenth Anniversary Convention, Colorado, August 26-30, 1981 (Text : 15: 14)
  - National Women's Party, 1981-1984 (Text : 15: 15)
  - New Country Foundation Conference, July 15, 1995 (Text : 16: 1)
  - New Directions in Environmental Policy Conference - John Baden, 1987 (Text : 16: 2)
  - New School Panel, September, 1993 (Text : 16: 3)
  - Rand and Libertarianism, 1997 (Text : 16: 4)
  - Reclaiming the Mainstream, 1992 (Text : 16: 5)
  - Reclaiming the Mainstream Talks - book pub, 1993 (Text : 16: 6)
  - Visions of Liberty Series, 1992 (Text : 16: 7)
  - Williams College, circa 1986 (Text : 16: 8)
  - Women's Freedom Network Conference, October 12-13, 1996 (Text : 16: 9)
  - Women and Law Course File, 1992, 1997
    Lesson plans and materials from a course taught by Joan Kennedy Taylor at the New School entitled, “Women and the Law.”
    - Women and the Law - 19th Century Era (week 1), circa 1997 (Text : 16: 10)
    - Women and the Law - Equality v. difference, theoretical arguments (week 2), circa 1997 (Text : 16: 11)
    - Women and the Law - Pregnancy Debate, (week 3), circa 1997 (Text : 16: 12)
    - Women and the Law - Sexual Harassment, (week 4 and 5), circa 1997 (Text : 16: 13)
    - Women and the Law - Pornography, (week 6 and 7), circa 1997 (Text : 17: 1)
    - Women and the Law - Prostitution, (week 8), circa 1997 (Text : 17: 2)
    - Women and the Law - Rape, (week 9 and 10), circa 1997 (Text : 17: 3)
    - Women and the Law - Birth Control and Abortion, (week 11), circa 1997 (Text : 17: 4)
    - Women and the Law - Abortion (week 12 and 13), circa 1997 (Text : 17: 5)
    - Women and the Law - General Info, circa 1997 (Text : 17: 6)
    - Women's National Book Association - "Books that Changed Lives,", 1994 (Text : 17: 7)
    - Women's National Book Association - Panel, 1991 (Text : 17: 8)
    - Women's Studies Program, October 3, 1992 (Text : 17: 9)
- Writing and Publishing File, 1961-2001
  Composed of articles, essays, monographs, and reviews written and edited by Kennedy Taylor. Some of the writings in this section include those of other authors, mainly Nathaniel Branden, Roy A. Childs, Charles Murray and Elizabeth Roderz. Series also includes files documenting Kennedy Taylor’s work in the publishing world.
  - Publishing Work file, 1980-2000
    Composed of documents pertaining to Joan Kennedy Taylor’s work in the publishing world. Includes book catalogues, correspondence, publicity work files, and copies of manuscripts that Kennedy Taylor was asked to review.
    - After Apartheid, 1986-1988 (Text : 17: 10)
    - After Apartheid, 1986-1988 (Text : 18: 1)
    - After Apartheid - Laissez Fair Books ad, circa 1980 (Text : 18: 2)
    - Ann Stone, 1993 (Text : 18: 3)
    - "The Bell Curve", 1994 (Text : 18: 4)
    - Beverly Pabst - Heaton Hall, 1988 (Text : 18: 5)
    - The Book Business, 1986-1990 (Text : 18: 6)
    - Business Letters, 1987 (Text : 18: 7)
    - Charles Murray, 1984 (Text : 18: 8)
    - Charles Murray Promo, 1983-1986 (Text : 18: 9)
    - Chassell, Bob, 1990 (Text : 18: 10)
    - Correspondence - women's history, 1981-1992 (Text : 18: 11)
    - Joe Le Blanc - letters and chapters, 1989-1990 (Text : 18: 12)
    - Laissez Faire Books, 1992-1998 (Text : 18: 13)
    - Listings and Catalogs, 1993-1999 (Text : 19: 1-2)
    - McElroy and Smith, 1998 (Text : 19: 3)
    - Proposals, 1983-1984 (Text : 19: 4)
    - Randall Fitzgerald's Privatization Book, 1987 (Text : 19: 5)
    - Sharon Presley, 1999-2000 (Text : 20: 1-2)
    - Social Philosophy and Policy Center, 1986 (Text : 20: 3)
    - Super Parents, Super Children, 1987 (Text : 20: 4)
    - Women's National Book Association, 1984-1991 (Text : 20: 5-6)
    - Work for Sean Konecky, 1986 (Text : 20: 7)
  - Writings by Joan Kennedy Taylor, 1961-2001
    Comprised of articles, essays, manuscripts and monographs written by Joan Kennedy Taylor. Large portion of the series includes publication and book reviews written by Kennedy Taylor.
    - "America's Struggle Against Poverty," review for Inquiry, 1982 (Text : 20: 8)
    - Articles for Reason on women's rights, 1986-1988 (Text : 20: 9)
    - Articles for Tibor's book, 1980 (Text : 20: 10)
    - "Ayn Rand View of the Concept of Feminism,", 1996-1998 (Text : 21: 1)
    - "A Bulwark Against the State,", 1986 (Text : 21: 2)
    - The Canterville Ghost, 1976 (Text : 21: 3)
    - Civil Liberties and Civil Rights, circa 1990 (Text : 21: 4)
    - Ed Clark, Position Papers - Feminism, circa 1980 (Text : 21: 5)
    - Comment on Block's review of, "Feminism and Freedom,", 1989 (Text : 21: 6)
    - Conservative Book Club, 1987 (Text : 21: 7)
    - "Crusaders for Capitalism,", 1987 (Text : 21: 8)
    - Die Zeit review, 1994-1995 (Text : 21: 9)
    - Early Drafts of, The Wall Street Journal reviews, 1985 (Text : 21: 10)
    - "The Entrepreneurial Alternative,", 1984 (Text : 21: 11)
    - ERA articles, 1977-1982 (Text : 21: 12)
    - "Erotica or Pornography?" Against the Wall, circa 1980 (Text : 22: 1)
    - Feminists in the Sex Industry, 1996-1998 (Text : 22: 2)
    - Free Inquiry Article on Feminism and Humanism, 1990 (Text : 22: 3)
    - "From Adam Smith to the Wealth of America,", 1985 (Text : 22: 4)
    - Frontlines piece on ERA, 1980 (Text : 22: 5)
    - Government Gets Religious (includes uncut 1st draft - Worldwide Church of God), 1970 (Text : 22: 6)
    - "The Hostile Workplace,", circa 1990 (Text : 22: 7)
    - "How I Became a Feminist,", 1992 (Text : 22: 8)
    - Interview with June O'Neill, Manhattan Report, 1984 (Text : 22: 9)
    - JKT - professional, 1981-1996 (Text : 22: 10)
    - Liberty on Child Pornography Prevention Act, 1996 (Text : 22: 11)
    - Libertarian Review, articles and reviews, 1977-1979 (Text : 22: 12)
    - "Memories of Ayn Rand," written for Fragments but withdrawn, 1984-1990 (Text : 22: 13)
    - Never published letter for New York City magazine, 1992 (Text : 22: 14)
    - News Releases and Ads, 1992 (Text : 22: 15)
    - Notebook, circa 1980 (Text : 22: 16)
    - Notes for book with Jenny, 1983 (Text : 22: 17)
    - On Abortion, Free Inquiry, 1996 (Text : 22: 18)
    - Other Writings by JKT, 1961-1992 (Text : 22: 19)
    - Other Writings by JKT, 1977-1987 (Text : 23: 1)
    - "Protecting Minors from Free Speech,", 1997 (Text : 23: 2)
    - Pornography Victims Compensation Act, article for the Authors Guild Bulletin, 1992 (Text : 23: 3)
    - "Rational Compromise,", circa 1970 (Text : 23: 4)
    - Reader's Digest Book, 1986-1987 (Text : 23: 5)
    - Reclaiming the Mainstream,correspondence, 1990-1992 (Text : 23: 6)
    - Reclaiming the Mainstream, old file (contract, early letters, notes), 1987-1992 (Text : 23: 7)
    - Reclaiming the Mainstream, reviews, listings, quotes, 1991-1994 (Text : 23: 8)
    - Reclaiming the Mainstream, Notes, Etc., 1991-1992 (Text : 24: 1)
    - "Respecting Diversity,", 1981 (Text : 24: 2)
    - Reviews, 1980-2000
      Literary reviews of writings of various authors, done by Joan Kennedy Taylor.
      - Reviews, 1992-2000 (Text : 24: 3)
      - Review of Branden Communication tapes, circa 1980 (Text : 24: 4)
      - Review of, "Defending Pornography: Free Speech, Sex and the Fight for Women's Rights," by Nadine Strosser, 1995 (Text : 24: 5)
      - Review of, "An Eye for an Eye,", 1993 (Text : 24: 6)
      - Review of, "A Feminist Defense of the Free Market,", circa 1990 (Text : 24: 7)
      - Review of, "Fire with Fire,", 1994 (Text : 24: 8)
      - Review of, "Free Enterprise Without Poverty,", 1982 (Text : 24: 9)
      - Review of, "Honoring the Self,", 1984 (Text : 24: 10)
      - Review of, "In Pursuit...,", 1989 (Text : 24: 11)
      - Review of, "Judgment in Berlin,", 1984 (Text : 24: 12)
      - Review of, "Judgment Day: My Years with Ayn Rand,", 1989 (Text : 24: 13)
      - Review of, "A Lesser Life,", 1981 (Text : 24: 14)
      - Review of, "Mindspell,", 1983 (Text : 24: 15)
      - Review of, (never published) Gilder's "Men and Marriage,", 1986 (Text : 24: 16)
      - Review of, "The Psychology of Individualism,", 1985 (Text : 24: 17)
      - Review of, "Reason Versus Mysticism,", 1997 (Text : 24: 18)
      - Review of, "Sex, Art, and American Culture,", 1993 (Text : 24: 19)
      - Review of, "The State Against Blacks,", 1982 (Text : 24: 20)
      - Review of, "Strange Justice,", 1995 (Text : 24: 21)
      - Review of, "Taking Responsibility," by Nathaniel Brandon, 1996 (Text : 24: 22)
      - Review of, "A Tale of the Wind: A novel of nineteenth century France,", 1996 (Text : 24: 23)
      - Review of, "The Truants: Adventures Among the Intellectuals,", circa 1982 (Text : 24: 24)
      - Review of, "Victims of Memory,", 1994 (Text : 24: 25)
      - Review of, "Why are They Lying to Our Children,", 1985 (Text : 24: 26)
      - Review of, "The Woman Behind the Welfare State,", 1984 (Text : 25: 1)
    - Response to Sheaffer, Free Inquiry, 1994-1995 (Text : 25: 2)
    - Rutherford, "Why I am a Feminist,", 1993 (Text : 25: 3)
    - Sexual Harassment, 1992-1996 (Text : 25: 4)
    - Sexual Harassment, 1996-1997 (Text : 25: 5)
    - Sexual Harassment Book meterial, pending, 1997-2000 (Text : 25: 6)
    - Sexual Harassment for Inquiry, 1984 (Text : 25: 7)
    - Sexual Harassment, Paperback, 2001 (Text : 25: 8)
    - "We the People," open piece for Bill, 1985 (Text : 25: 9)
    - "The Welfare Mystique," Inquiry, 1982 (Text : 25: 10)
  - Writing by Others, 1977-2000
    Composed of articles, essays, manuscripts, monographs, and reviews by various personal and professional associates of Kennedy Taylor. Series also includes student manuscripts from a fiction essay writing contest sponsored by Institute of Humane Studies, which Joan Kennedy Taylor was the judge of.
    - Roy A. Childs Jr., 1983-1992 (Text : 26: 1)
    - Roy A. Childs Jr., 1983 (Text : 27: 2)
    - "Developmental Psychology Today,", circa 1990 (Text : 26: 3)
    - Full Context Interview, 1993 (Text : 26: 4)
    - Institute of Humane Studies, Fiction Essay Contest Judges, 1994 (Text : 26: 5)
    - Emilia Nordtvedt, 1977 (Text : 26: 6)
    - "The Passion of Ayn Rand,", 1986 (Text : 26: 7)
    - People I Know, 1980-1998 (Text : 26: 8)
    - People I Know, 1981-1985 (Text : 27: 1)
    - Rand Obituary, 1982 (Text : 27: 2)
    - "Never Was," by Elizabeth Roderz, circa 2000 (Text : 27: 3)
    - Christina Sommers, 1990 (Text : 27: 4)